

Neha Gupta

Marketing Team Manager

female

Profile

A marketing professional with +7 years of industrial exposure in handling activities with focus on bottom-line performance as well as optimal utilisation of resources.

An effective communicator with excellent analysing skills and ability to relate & coordinate with people at all levels of the business.

Seeking challenging position in Sales and Marketing that can contribute towards the growth of the organisation and further my capabilities.

PROFILE: A supremely motivated and responsible individual with a strong vision, enthusiasm and an unquenchable thirst to achieve a successful outcome for an organisation. This vision has included corporate strategy creation, devising innovative ideas and executing it in a unique manner and extensive exposure in business development, marketing and sales activities. These capabilities would be major assets to any esteemed organisation seeking to increase their marketing and sales penetration.

Education

MBA from Indian Institute of Planning & Management

B.Sc Chem (Hons) from DELHI UNIVERSITY in 2011

Class XII; 2008 CBSE BOARD; 75%

Class X; 2006 CBSE BOARD; 84%

Professional Experience

District Manager - Key Accounts, INFOCOM NETWORK LTD

10/2022 – present | Delhi, India

- Oversee a team of 8 customer service Associate's and ensure they are providing an exceptional client experience
- Developing effective communication platforms for clients and team.
- Inspiring repeat business from existing clients.
- Monitoring and measuring client satisfaction.
- Offering advice to clients on services and products.
- upgrading their services on regular basis by pitching and converting them into higher packages.

- Renewing their services after their tenure is over
- Resolve complex client problems or disputes in a professional manner
- Create monthly and quarterly departmental reports to determine whether KPIs are being met and where there is room for improvement

Marketing Team Manager, Venus consulting solutions pvt ltd

10/2016 - 09/2022 | Noida, India

- Leading a team of 7 members with increased customer satisfaction and sales.
- Utilised social media, email and web to notify people of sales promotions, events and product launches.
- Monitored sales team performance and provided constructive feedback.
- Led sales team to exceed quarterly sales goals.
- Reported sales data to upper management for review.
- Led regular team meetings to keep sales personnel motivated with tips, techniques and relevant information.
- Built strong team by recruiting and developing top sales talent.
- Forecasted sales to management and collaborated to build effective sales team.
- Implemented new marketing initiatives to drive sales and improve overall performance.
- Achieved and exceeded sales goals through dedication to identifying and pursuing new opportunities.
- B2B and B2C Sales Responsibilities
- Studied product and local markets to adjust sales pitches and adapt strategies for optimized sales.
- Participation in the hiring process of new staff, CV screening, Interviews, on-boarding and training of new employees
- Employer branding and employee retention throughout their employment in the team
- Constant attention to employee motivation, growth and work-life balance of employees with long-term employment in mind
- Meeting with the corporate and individuals and converting them into paid client
- · Following up with customers regularly regarding services scheduled and payments due
- Ensure end to end support to all clients till delivery for the report
- Give sales presentations to a range of prospective clients

Sr Executive, Indiamart

11/2014 - 09/2016 | Noida, India

- Generating meeting with the clients over call
- Maintained client records
- Solving client queries about the product and services over calls and Emails
- coordination with the field executive
- Improved operations through consistent hard work and dedication.
- Exceeded goals through effective task prioritization and great work ethic.
- Onboarded new temps by entering employee information into systems.
- Led projects and analyzed data to identify opportunities for improvement.
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.
- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and fast-paced atmosphere.
- Increased customer satisfaction by resolving issues.
- Actively listened to customers, handled concerns quickly and escalated major issues to supervisor.
- Learned new skills and applied to daily tasks to improve efficiency and productivity.
- Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently.

Operation Executive, *Policy bazaar*

10/2013 – 10/2014 | Gurgaon, India

- Conducted regular meetings with team to discuss issues, concerns and updates.
- Identified trends and assessed opportunities to improve processes and execution.

Skills

Direct marketing skills (Salesforce MS Office CRM Forecasting Business Development Customer Service Excellent communication skills Dynamic Team player Leadership qualities. Skilled internet researcher Analysis and Problem Solving Decision Making Skills Staff Management Brand development Client communication Corporate Communications Market Analysis),

Personal skill (Task Oriented Multi Tasking Relationship Building Time Management Storytelling Research / Information Gathering. Critical Thinking Problem Solving.)

Languages

English and Hindi

Projects

Projects undertaken

- PERFORMANCE ANALYSIS OF RELIANCE LIFE INSURANCE
- ROLE OF CAPITAL MARKET IN 21ST CENTURY
- FOR A TWO ASSET PORTFOLIO, DEMONSTRATE THAT PORTFOLIO RISK CAN BE REDUCED TO ZERO WITH PERFECT NEGATIVE CORRELATION
- TO ESTABLISH NIFTY CAN BE A MARKET SNAPSHOT

Summer Internship

TITLE - PERFORMANCE ANALYSIS OF RELIANCE INSURANCE COMPANY

COMPANY - RELIANCE INSURANCE COMPANY

ROLE -MANAGEMENT TRAINEE

DURATION- 45 DAYS

SYNOPSIS -I had learnt how to work in a business environment, calculation of risk and premium &got to know various insurance terms and policies

Extra Curricular Accolades

Won debate competition at school level Was SPOC at my internship Cleared IRDA exam during my internship Cleared capital market (dealers) module

Core Competencies:

Sales & Marketing:

Devising & effectuating sales & marketing programs / strategies to improve the product awareness and enhances business growth.

Prospecting customer approch, trends and competitor analysis.

Client Relationship Management:

Ensuring customer satisfaction by achieving delivery and service quality norms.